No volleyball player is a soloist. They're all parts of a larger orchestra. It's all over the moment even one of them starts to believe he's "special."
- Bernardo Rezende, coach of the Brazil
men's national volleyball team,
the top-ranked team in the world.
From the book "The People and System that made Brazilian Volleyball the Greatest"
by Yonemushi Noriko (Touhou Publishing)
もと速く動け
もと高く跳べ
Move faster!
Jump higher!
More... more...
Give me more!
なんでなんで跳んでないんだ
Why?
Why won't you jump?
(金田一)もううんざりなんだよ
この自己中の王様が
We've had it up to here with you,
you egocentric king!
ピピピピｯ(目覚まし時計のｱﾗｰﾑ)
は
ピピピピピピピピ
(清水)おはようございます
(縁下)ちわす
Good morning.
Hey.
(日向翔陽)
美女だあの美女が来た
It's that hottie. That hottie's here!
Kiyoko, you look lovely today.
Hey, think she might be the team manager?
なあなあやぱ
あの人マネジャかな
I love it when she ignores me!
(澤村)よしじゃあ始めるぞ
All right. Let's get started.
I'll be on Tsukishima's team.
月島たちの方には俺が入るから
えキャプテンが
Are you serious, Captain?!
(澤村)はは大丈夫だよ
攻撃力は田中の方が上だから
Relax.
Tanaka's a better attacker than me.
でも手は抜かないからな
But know that I won't go easy on you guys.
(月島)ああんん
小さいのと田中さん
Out of the midget and Tanaka, which one should we target—
どち先に潰
抑えましょうかぁ
er, keep in check first?
ん
(月島)あそうそう
Oh, how could I forget?
王様が負けるところも
見たいですねぇ
We'd like to see the King on his knees in defeat too, right?
Keep it down, Tsukki! What if they heard you?
(山口)ちょツキ
聞こえてるんじゃヤバいよ
(月島)聞こえるように
言てんだろうが
I want them to hear it, dude.
I sure hope they lose their heads.
冷静さを欠いてくれると
ありがたいなぁ
(澤村)
月島いい性格の悪さしてるねぇ
I see you're quite the ass, Tsukishima.
The lonesome king who lost all of his lackeys, in particular, is a sight for sore eyes.
(月島)
特に家来たちに見放されて
一人ぼちになちゃた王様が
見ものですよね
(田中)
ねえねえ今の聞いたぁ
Goodness gracious me.
Did you hear that?
あんなこと言ちゃて
Can you believe what he just said?
月島君てばもうほんと
Jeez, that Tsukishima.
He's so...
dead!
(田中)すり潰す
べぇ
Episode Four:
The View From the Summit
Take this!
そらぁ
うわ
(木下)
あのでかい１年吹飛ばした
He just destroyed that massive first-year.
He's putting in a lot more power than usual!
≪いつもよりすげぇパワ
Hell yeah!
うしゃ
(菅原)田中ウザい
Stop that, Tanaka.
(縁下)喜びすぎ
(木下)いちいち脱ぐな
Tone it down, man.
Keep your shirt on.
Might've been a bad idea to provoke him.
(澤村)田中あおたのは
失敗だたかもね
(月島)ち
ピ
前前
オケ
The front!
Got it.
≪俺だて俺だて
Me too...
Me too!
日向
≪トスが上がるんだ
Hinata!
He's gonna set for me too!
≪記念すべき
高校の試合一発目
And I'm gonna kick off my first match in high school with a bang—
え
(２人)あ
≪決めてやる
with my first spike!
≪ここにもまた
Not here too...
There's a massive, massive wall in front of me again.
高い高い壁
この間もびくりしたけど
君よく跳ぶねぇ
It really surprised me the other night as well, but boy, you sure can fly.
それであとほんの３０センチ
身長があれば
Now if only you were just thirty centimeters taller,
you could've been a superstar.
スパスタだたかもね
く
≪でかくたて相手は一人≫
He may be huge, but he's only one guy.
O-Once more!
ももう一本
≪次は決める
≫バチ
This time, I'll score!
(菅原)またブロク
(縁下)これで何本目だ
Another block?
Kageyama/Hinata    Tsukishima/Yamaguchi
How many does that make it, now?
Nice, Tsukki.
(木下)田中の方は
結構決まてるけどなぁ
Tanaka seems to be scoring at will, though.
Nice block, Tsukishima.
Damn it!
Thank you.
≪こいつ思た以上にやるな≫
He's better than I expected.
(月島)ほらほら
ブロクに掛かりぱなしだよ
Look at you.
Your team keeps getting blocked.
王様のトスやればいいじゃん
What happened to the King's sets?
敵を置き去りにするトス
You know, the ones opponents can't keep up with.
And the ones teammates can't keep up with, either.
ついでに
味方も置き去りにしちゃうやつね
Shut up.
うるせぇんだよ
(澤村)山口ナイサ
Give us a good serve, Yamaguchi!
ピ
(山口)くあ
ち
(山口)ごごめんツキ
S-Sorry, Tsukki.
ピ
(澤村)ドンマイドンマイ
Don't worry about it.
速い攻撃なんか使わなくても
I don't need fast attacks
勝てやるよ
to win.
行け殺人サブ
Give 'em the killer serve!
(菅原)≪影山のジｬンプサブか
強烈だたな≫
Kageyama's jump serve, huh?
It was pretty overwhelming.
≪まとめて点稼いでやる
I'm gonna score a bunch of points all at once!
Go!
≪行け
く
げ
Ack.
(月島)山口
(山口)任せろツキ
Yamaguchi.
I got this, Tsukki!
ピ
くそ
Dammit.
Nice set, Tsukki.
大地さんの武器は
安定したレシブだ
Steady receives are Daichi's forte.
Good job, Yamaguchi.
He's an incredible defender.
守備力はハンパねぇぞ
(澤村)何点か稼げるかと思たか
Were you expecting to score a few points in a row?
う
(澤村)突出した才能はなくても
I don't have any outstanding talents,
but I've spent two years more than you guys etching this receiving skill into my body.
２年分お前らより長く
体に刷り込んできたレシブだ
簡単に崩せると思うなよ
カカコいい
Don't think it's going down without a fight.
S-So cool!
(月島)ほら王様そろそろ
本気出した方がいいんじゃない
Come on, King.
Don't you think it's about time you pulled out all the stops?
はあ何なんだお前
この間から突かかりやがて
What's your problem, man?
You keep trying to pick a fight with him.
王様のトスてなんだ
What the hell is the "King's set"?
君こいつがなんで
王様て呼ばれてるか知らないの
Don't you know why he's called the King?
こいつが
なんかすげぇうまいから
Well, for some reason, he's really good.
ほかの学校のヤツらがビビて
そう呼んだとかじゃないの
The other schools must've gotten scared of his skills and named him that, no?
あははそう思てるヤツも
結構いると思うけどね
I'm sure there are a lot of people who think that way,
でも噂じゃあ
コト上の王様て異名
but rumor has it that he was given the nickname of
"King of the Court" by the guys from Kitagawa First—
北川第一のヤツらが
付けたらしいじゃん
王様のチｰムメイトがさ意味は
the King's teammates.
It means...
自己中の王様横暴な独裁者
"Egocentric King."
"Oppressive Despot."
噂だけは聞いたことがあたけど
あの試合を見て納得いたよ
I'd only heard rumors about it at first,
but I was convinced after watching that match.
横暴が行きすぎてあの決勝
ベンチに下げられてたもんね
He got so oppressive that they had to sub him out of the final.
Kita First!
Kousen Academy                       Kitagawa First
(応援団)((北一北一
((コンコンコン))
(金田一)((く
((ピ
All right!
(２人)((よしゃ
≪くそブロクが高い≫
Damn. They can block really high.
≪なんとかして振り切らないと
もと速い攻撃で≫
We've gotta shake them off somehow.
We need to attack much faster—
≪ブロクが
ついてこられなくなるくらい≫
fast enough to be unblockable.
Don't worry about it.
Sorry.
((もと速く
(金田一)((ち
Faster!
Give us a nice serve!
(光仙選手たち)((ナイｯサ
(金田一)((ライト
Right!
う
((うわ
Yes!
(金田一)((ふざけんな
ムチャすぎんだよお前のトス
What the hell's wrong with you?
Your sets are totally unreasonable!
打てなきゃ意味ねぇだろうが
What's the point if we can't spike them?!
All right! We only need one more point!
But we can't win unless we shake off their blocks!
≪けどこのブロク
振り切らなきゃ勝てねぇだろ
Almost there, guys!
Is this the end?
≪ここで終わんのか
≪ここで負けるのか
Am I going to lose here?
≪違う俺は全国へ行く
Hell no!
I'm gonna go to nationals!
((もと速く動け
もと高く跳べ
Move faster!
Jump higher!
((俺のトスに合わせろ
勝ちたいならは
Keep up with my sets if you wanna win!
(監督)((はぁ
(ﾅﾚｰｼｮﾝ)＜そして第１セト
相手のセトポイント＞
It was the first set.
Our opponents were on set point.
＜トスを上げた先＞
And when I made my set...
＜そこに誰もいなかた＞
there was nobody there to put it away.
＜あの日
コンビミスは何度かあた＞
We'd made many mistakes transitioning that day,
but what happened at the end wasn't a mistake.
＜でも
最後のあれはミスじゃない＞
＜あれは拒絶だ＞
It was a rejection.
＜もう
お前にはついていかないと
A rally where they put their arms up and said, "We're not following you anymore."
あいつらが俺に言た一球だた＞
((影山
Kageyama.
お前もうベンチ下がれ))
Sub out now.
(月島)クイク使わないのも
That why you've stopped making quick sets?
あの決勝のせいで
ビビてるとか
Are you chickening out due to what happened in that final?
てめぇ
さきからうるせぇんだよ
Hey, you've been running your mouth for a while now—
(澤村)田中
Tanaka.
せかくトス上げても
誰も跳んでないんじゃ
If you make sets, but nobody jumps to hit them—
That's right.
ああそうだ
トスを上げた先に
誰もいないつうのは
The idea of making a set only to find that there's nobody there...
心底怖ぇよ
terrifies me.
でもそれ中学の話でしょ
But that was back in junior high, right?
俺にはちゃんとトス上がるから
別に関係ない
So long as he sets for me,
I don't really care.
それよりどうやて
お前をぶち抜くかだけが問題だ
Breaking through your guard is a far more pressing issue!
ぷ
ははは
月島に勝て
ちゃんと部活入て
We're gonna beat Tsukishima and join this team for real.
お前は正々堂々セタやる
そんで俺にトス上げる
You'll get to play setter with your head held high,
and then you'll set for me.
それ以外になんかあんのか
Does anything else matter?
(月島)そういう
いかにも純粋でますぐな感じ
That kinda pure and straightforward shtick really gets on my nerves.
イラとする
ピ
(月島)
気合いで身長差は埋まらない
Your spirit won't make up for your lack of height.
If you think hard work trumps all else,
努力で
全部なんとかなると思たら
大間違いなんだよ
then you're sorely mistaken.
任せろ
田中さん
Got it.
Tanaka.
(２人)俺に上げろ
Gimme!
Bring it on!
≪どちに上げる
Who should I set for?
Over here!
Hinata can't beat Tsukishima head-on yet.
≪日向はまだ
真向勝負で月島に勝てない≫
Tanaka!
田中さん
影山
Kageyama!
≪そこに誰も
There was... nobody there...
いるぞ
I'm here!
う
おお
え
あぶね空振るところだた
That was close.
I nearly whiffed that one.
アウトだけど
お前何をいきなり
It went out, though.
What was that for?!
But the ball did come to me!
でもちゃんとボル来た
中学のことなんか知らねぇ
Who cares about junior high?
I'll take whatever sets I can get.
俺にとてはどんなトスだて
ありがたいトスなんだ
And I'll be grateful for all of them!
俺はどこにだて跳ぶ
どんなボルだて打つ
I'll jump anywhere.
I'll spike any ball!
だから
So...
俺にトス持てこい
set for me!
Haikyuu !!
(菅原)≪今影山は田中の方に
上げようとしてたはずなのに
I'm pretty sure Kageyama was about to set for Tanaka there.
と動きに
とさに反応して
But he still reacted instantly to Hinata's voice
and movement and made such an accurate set.
あそこまで正確なトスを
≪今のところ口の悪さばか
目立ちゃてるけど
His foul mouth's been the only thing getting attention so far,
やぱ影山すごい
but he really is amazing!
You guys can run quick plays?!
おいお前らクイｯク使えんのか
クイク
(田中)今みたいな速い攻撃だよ
"Quick plays"?
Fast attacks like the one you just did!
No way.
全然俺ポンて
山なりに上がるトスしか
I've only ever spiked slow and looping sets.
打たことないです
でも今やたろそれにお前
But you just did it!
Besides, didn't you once spike a messed-up set from that beginner on your junior high team?
中学んとき素人セタの
ミスたトス打たろ
ああいう
えでも
Stuff like that.
Oh, I don't remember how I did that.
どうやたかは覚えてないです
(田中)え
でも俺
どんなトスでも打ちますよ
But I'll spike any set that comes my way.
You hear me?
打つからな
合わせたこともないのに
速攻なんて無理だろ
We've never practiced plays.
Running a quick one is impossible.
≪は今無理て言た
Did he just say "impossible"?
≪こいつ
無理て単語知てんのか
Does he even know what that word means?
You're being weird!
なんだお前変
そんな弱気なの気持ち悪い変
You're acting so timid it's giving me the creeps! Weirdo!
うせぇな
Oh, shut it.
王様らしくないんじゃない
This isn't like you, King.
今打ち抜いてやるから
待てろ
Just you wait! I'm gonna break through your defenses!
またそんな
ムキになちゃてさぁ
There you go, getting all worked up again.
なんでもがむしゃらにやれば
いいてもんじゃないでしょ
"Try and try until you succeed" sounds nice on paper,
but it doesn't always work like that.
人には向き不向きが
あるんだからさ
Everyone has things they're just not cut out for.
君明らかに
スパイカに向いてないでしょ
And you're clearly not fit to be a spiker.
んん
確かに
Maybe.
I mean, be it back in junior high or in this match,
I kept getting blocked no matter how much I jumped.
中学んときも今も俺
跳んでも跳んでも
ブロクに止められてばかだ
バレボルは高さが必要
And I know that a volleyball player needs to be tall.
Doesn't matter how high you can jump.
It'll never make up for a massive difference in height.
いくら高く跳べても
圧倒的な身長差は埋まんねぇ
だけど
Even so,
あんなふうになりたいて
思ちゃたんだよ
I ended up wanting to be like that!
だから不利とか不向きとか
関係ないんだ
So I don't care if I'm disadvantaged or not cut out for it.
この体で戦て勝て勝て
I wanna fight using my own body.
I wanna keep winning...
もといぱいコトにいたい
and stay on the court as much as I can!
≪嫌だ≫
≪俺はまだ
No way.
I still...
(２人)
≪まだコトに立ていたい
I still wanna stand on the court!
だからその方法がないんでしょ
精神論じゃないんだて
But you don't have the means to do so.
We're not talking psychology here.
気持ちで身長差が埋まんの
リベロになるなら話は別だけど
Your feelings aren't gonna make up for your lack of height.
Though I guess it's a different story if you wanna be a libero.
((俺にトス持てこい
Set for me!
Breaking through the wall that stands in the spiker's way...
スパイカの前の壁を切り開く
そのためのセタだ
is what a setter is for!
ん
うわななんだよ影山
Wh-What is it, Kageyama?
ちょ痛ぇよ放せ
お落ち着け影山
Hey, that hurts!
Lemme go!
Calm down, Kageyama!
何すんい
いいか
What are you—
Listen up.
打てないならかわすぞ
If we can't break through, we'll just have to go around.
お前のありたけの運動能力と
反射神経で俺のトスを打て
Use every last bit of your agility and reflexes to spike my sets.
(田中)
はあそれ速攻の説明かよ
Is that how you explain a quick attack?!
分かた
(田中)うそつけ分かてねぇだろ
Gotcha.
Pull the other one! You didn't get a thing!
(２人)とりあえずやてみます
なんだお前
We'll just try it anyway!
What's gotten into you?
You were totally depressed just a minute ago.
さきまで
ガチへこみしてたくせに
へこんでません
うそつけ
I wasn't.
Pull the other one!
All right.
よしゃやてやんよ
Give us a good serve!
Let's do this.
≪こいつの反射とスピドなら
速いトスだて打てるはずだ≫
Considering his speed and reflexes,
he should be able to spike quick sets.
≪よしトス来い
どこにでも来い
Okay, bring on the sets. Bring 'em on anywhere!
Give us a good serve, Tsukki!
≪サインとかまだねぇしな
とりあえず
We haven't even figured out the signs yet, but whatever.
≪よしそち側に
トス上がるんだな≫
Oh, so he's gonna make a set there.
Hinata.
≪よし吉田のおばちゃんの
サブより弱い≫
Great. That serve's not as good as Mrs. Yoshida's.
Now I just gotta jump over here...
≪そんでこちに跳
≪えこんな速いの
Huh? It's that fast?
おい何してるもと速
What's wrong with you?!
Move faster—
出た王様のトス
ち
Oh, look. There's the King's set.
最初から
うまくいくわけねぇだろ
As if it was ever gonna work right off the bat!
I'm not sure it ever will.
(月島)それはどうかな
くよしゃ触う
Yay, I touched it!
漁業かこら
What are you, a fish?!
うぅ
全然タイミング分かんねぇよ
Man, I have no idea what the right timing is.
お前反応速いんだからもと
こうバと来いよグワと
Dude, you have incredible reflexes! Be more like, "bam"! Wham!
バなのかグワなのか
どちだ
Bam or wham? Pick one!
That's not the point!
(田中)重要なのはそこじゃねぇよ
(菅原)影山
Kageyama.
そんじゃあ
中学んときと同じだよ
You're repeating what you did in junior high.
あえと
Uh, well...
Hinata's got reflexes, speed, and an amazing vertical.
日向には反射もスピドも
ついでにバネもある
慣れれば速い攻撃だて
If he can get used to quick plays...
日向の
そのすばしこさていう武器
Don't you think your sets are hindering his agility?
お前のトスが
殺しちゃてるんじゃないの
(菅原)日向には技術も経験もない
う菅原さん
Hinata has neither volleyball skills nor experience.
Sugawara?
(菅原)中学でお前に
ギリギリ合わせてくれた
He's not like your talented junior high teammates.
優秀なプレヤとは違う
でも素材はピカイチ
But he's got great potential.
え
そんな天才とか大げさです
Me? A prodigy? No way!
へへへ
(田中)言てねぇよ
He didn't call you one.
(菅原)お前の腕があたらさ
With your skills,
can't you take his unique, uh, talents and... well...
なんつうかもと
日向の持ち味ていうか
才能ていうか
そういうのをもとこう
Uh...
えと
(田中)スガさんファイト
Hang in there, Suga!
なんかうまいこと
使てやれんじゃないの
Can't you put them to good use?
(菅原)
俺お前と同じセタだから
I'm a setter too, so when I watched
that match last year, I was intimidated.
去年の試合
お前見てビビたよ
ずばぬけたセンスと
ボルコントロル
By your outstanding playmaking, ball control,
そんで何より
敵ブロクの動きを
and most of all...
your vision and decision-making ability that let
you see right through your opponents' defense.
冷静に見極める目と判断力
I don't have any of that.
俺には全部ないものだ
That's not true, Suga—
そんなことないすよスガさ
田中一回聞いとくべ
Tanaka.
Let's hear him out.
You have the skills,
(菅原)技術があてやる気も
ありすぎるぐらいあて
the motivation to win,
何より周りを見る
優れた目を持ているお前に
and above all, incredible vision.
仲間のことが
見えないはずがない
There's no way you can't see
through your own teammates!
Put him to good use?
≪なんかうまいことて
なんだ
But how?!
((でもちゃんとボル来た
But the ball did come to me!
俺は
おおう
I...
Y-Yeah?
I envy your athleticism.
お前の運動神経が羨ましい
はあ
What?
だから宝の持ち腐れのお前が
腹立たしい
It pisses me off that you're letting it all go to waste.
Excuse me?
はあ
それならお前の能力
So I'm gonna put all of your abilities to good use.
俺が全部使てみせる
え
なんだ
What the?
お前のいちばんのスピド
いちばんのジャンプで跳べ
Give me your top speed and your best jumps.
ボルは俺が持ていく
And I'll send the ball your way.
持ていくて何
どういうこと
Send it my way?
What do you mean?
お前はただ
ブロクのいないとこに
Just run as fast as you can to an area
they're not marking, jump as high as you can,
マクスの速さと高さで跳ぶ
そんで全力スイングだ
and swing your arm as hard as you can.
俺のトスは見なくていい
ボルには合わせなくていい
No need to keep an eye on my sets.
No need to care about what the ball's doing.
Say what?
はあ
ボル見なきゃ空振るじゃん
I'll just swing and miss if I don't watch.
かもな
うおい
Maybe.
Hey!
But I still wanna try this.
でもやてみたい
分かた
Gotcha.
まだ何かやるつもりか
王様の自己中トスなんて
They're still up to something?
I wish they'd hurry up and figure out that nobody can hit the King's egocentric sets.
誰も打てないてば
だよね
You can say that again.
≪何するつもりだ
少なくともあのトスじゃ
What are they trying to do?
At the very least, there's no way Hinata can keep up with those sets right now.
今の日向が合わせるのは
無理だぞ≫
Give us a good serve!
Kageyama/Hinata    Tsukishima/Yamaguchi
(山口)ナイサ一本
すぅふぅ
≪すげぇ集中≫
What amazing concentration...
≪見ろ見ろ≫
Watch.
See through it!
≪ブロクの位置は
ボルの位置は
Where are the blockers?
Where's the ball?
≪スパイカの位置は
次にどう動くどこに跳ぶ
Where's the spiker?
What will he do next?
Where will he jump?
≪こいつのジャンプのてぺんは
どこだ
Where is the absolute peak of his jump?
≪今この位置
このタイミングこの角度で
This is it!
This is the position, the timing, and the angle!
あ
よし
は
Yeah!
手に手に当たた
It...
It hit my hand!
うおすげぇ
大げさだな
He's so melodramatic.
Hey...
おい今日向目ぇつぶてたぞ
Hinata had his eyes closed just now!
(３人)はあ
(月島)あのどういう
Um, what do you mean?
(澤村)ジャンプする瞬間から
スイングするまでの間
He kept his eyes closed from the moment he jumped to the moment he hit the ball.
日向は目をつぶてたつまり
That means Kageyama made a pinpoint set into
Hinata's palm when he wasn't even looking at the ball!
影山がボルを全く見ていない
日向の手のひらに
ピンポイントに
トスを上げたんだ
And he delivered it with perfect accuracy
at the exact moment Hinata swung his arm.
スイングの瞬間に合わせて
寸分の狂いもなく
はあ
すげぇすげぇなあ何
Awesome!
What was that just now?
今の何当たたんだけど手に
今俺のなあ
The ball just hit my hand!
おいお前
目ぇつぶてたてなんだ
Hey!
Why did you have your eyes closed?!
お前が
ボル見るなて言たんだろ
You told me not to look at the ball.
I end up ball watching when my eyes are open, so I closed them.
目ぇ開けてるとどうしても
ボルに目が行くから
確かに言たけど
I did say that, but...
But hey, we pulled it off.
でも今の成功だろ何が悪い
それはそうだけど
What's the problem?
Yeah, we did, but who the hell
trusts another guy completely?!
１００％信じるなんて
できるか普通
I don't know what else to do right now!
だて今信じる以外の方法
分かんねぇもん
((クソ下手くそなヤツ
You suck!
((お前は３年間何やてたんだ
What have you been doing for the last three years?!
≪こいつの
あのバネも機動力も
I can bring his vertical and his agility to life
What the hell was that, dude? It was amazing!
俺のトスなら生かせる≫
with my sets!
Good.
よし日向のスパイクが決まれば
If Hinata can land his spikes, the markers will split up, which will make it easier for Tanaka to score too.
マクが分散して
田中さんも打ちやすくなる
おお
(田中)よしゃ
Yeah!
Great!
There's absolutely no camaraderie between us,
俺たちには
信頼関係なんて微塵もないが
う
(田中)え
but know that I'll keep sending the ball your way.
次もボルは俺が持ていく
Trust me and jump.
信じて跳べ
うん
'Kay.
≪ここだ
びゃ
Now!
悪い
My bad.
Kageyama/Hinata    Tsukishima/Yamaguchi
(縁下)うん
さきのはまぐれかなぁ
Was that earlier one just a fluke?
(菅原)でも確実に
トスの精度は上がてきてるよ
His sets are definitely getting more accurate.
(縁下)そうですかね
(菅原)うん
Really?
Yeah.
Here, Hinata.
≪くそ
今度はネトから離しすぎた≫
Dammit.
Oh, thanks.
I set it too far from the net this time.
Ouch.
≪やぱ簡単じゃねぇな≫
This is harder than I thought.
≪コト上の全部を
常に把握しとくのもしんどいし≫
It's also a pain to keep track of everything that's happening on the court.
Are you all right?
Y-Yeah!
≪けど面白い
But it's so much fun!
The hell are you grinning for?
何ニヤニヤしてんだよ
ふざけんな顔面２回目だぞ
Screw you! That's the second time you hit my face!
理解不能
さきのはまぐれだろ
I can't believe this.
That one earlier was just dumb luck.
Yet they keep trying it over and over.
なのに懲りずに何回も
でもたぶん日向はまた
Hinata'll probably keep jumping without looking at the ball.
何回でもボルを見ないで
跳ぶんじゃないかな
You're not doing this on purpose, are you?
確かに理解不能だよな
Yeah, it certainly is unbelievable.
You know we've gotta win this, right?
It's not that easy to trust someone completely.
他人を１００％信じるなんて
そうできることじゃないもんな
Of course!
しかも因縁の相手なのにな
Especially not the guy you consider your greatest rival.
くそうまくいかねぇ
Damn, this just isn't working.
≪でもさきの手応え
Still...
That sensation when I hit the ball
right in the sweet spot was amazing.
≪ボルの芯を捉えたときの
手に伝わる重み
大好きな感触≫
I just love how it feels!
One more time.
≪もう一回もう一回≫
≪もう一回丁寧に≫
One more time, carefully...
≪スパイカが
最大限力を発揮できるトスを≫
I need to make a set that allows the
spiker to show the best of his ability.
I got this!
(田中)オライ任せろ
ナイスレシブ
Nice receive!
I bet he's gonna mess up trying to set for that midget again.
どうせ
またチビに上げて失敗だろ
田中さんだけマクしとけば
We just need to mark Tanaka—
はお前も来い
え
Get over here!
≪壁≫
A wall...
((いいか打ち抜けないなら
Listen up.
If we can't break through...
≪かわす
...we'll just have to go around!
≪長身の選手より
高さで劣るなら
So what if I'm not as tall as the others?
１センチを１ミリを１秒速く
I'll just jump one centimeter, one millimeter higher...
or be one second faster...
てぺんへそうすれば
to the peak!
That way, for that one moment,
今この瞬間だけ
ここがいちばん高い場所≫
I'll be at the highest point on the court!
＜目の前に立ちはだかる
高い高い壁＞
A massive, massive wall stands
in front of me, blocking my way.
＜その向こうは
どんな眺めだろうか＞
I wonder what the view is like on the other side.
＜どんなふうに
見えるのだろうか＞
What does it look like?
＜俺独りでは
決して見ることのできない
The view from the summit—
これが＞
it's something...
＜頂の景色＞
I'll never be able to see alone.
(２人)おし
Yes!
Next Episode Preview
Spiking with your eyes closed? Are you kidding me?
Unbelievable.
(田中)おいおいおい目ぇつぶて
スパイク打つとかありえねぇだろ
Things are getting crazy.
(月島)理解不能
Keep setting for me!
(菅原)なんかすごいことに
なてきちゃたな
Don't push your luck!
次も俺に持てこいぶ
Next time on Haikyuu!!:
Episode Five:
A Wimp's Anxiety
調子乗んな
ぐ
"A Wimp's Anxiety."